sirs.com 2002-12-08

# SIRS Publishing, Inc. - Privacy Statement

Last updated on September 10, 2001

SIRS Publishing, Inc. (SIRS) has adopted a privacy policy, which we have detailed in this Privacy Statement. SIRS created this policy to demonstrate our commitment to our customers' privacy. This statement defines the groups SIRS collects information from, addresses how this information is collected from SIRS Knowledge Source (SKS) and SIRS Discoverer (Discoverer) and for what purposes this information serves. 

" _Institution_ " is defined as the site licensing SIRS online databases through SKS and Discoverer, as defined in SIRS Publishing, Inc. Online License. 

" _End User_ " is defined as patrons, students, etc. authorized to use SIRS online databases through SKS and Discoverer under the "Terms of Use" in SIRS Publishing, Inc. Online License. Each Institution is responsible for obtaining parental or legal guardian permission for access to SKS and Discoverer. 

## Information SIRS Gathers and Tracks on End-Users

The Server aggregates the following End User search statistics: Query string, Search Program, Products Searched. This information is used to generate statistics for improving the content of the site, diagnosing problems with our servers, and for administering SKS and Discoverer. SIRS collects no End User information beyond what is listed above. 

End Users may request articles, graphics or other information from SIRS databases be e-mailed to their personal e-mail addresses. These e-mail addresses are temporarily stored for sending the information requested by the End-User and then automatically deleted from our system. SIRS prohibits any other e-mail transmission of SIRS databases, or portions thereof. 

End Users submitting e-mail questions to [webmaster@sirs.com](mailto:webmaster@sirs.com) are sent one-time responses. These e-mails are deleted from our systems once a response has been sent. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protections Act of 1998, SIRS does not knowingly collect any personal information from minors, except to respond to one-time requests. 

## Information SIRS Gathers and Tracks on Institutions

In SKS and Discoverer, cookies are used for maintaining session state and Institution authentication allowing seamless access for End-Users to and throughout the site. For registration accounts, the cookies remain on the workstation for a period of five (5) years. For password accounts, the cookie expires when the session ends. 

The server collects domain names and IP addresses of Institutions, which are utilized for generating broad statistical information on our customer base. This information combined with the End-User search statistics, are available to Institutions upon request. To request usage statistics, please submit your name, Institutions name, state, zip code, phone number and customer number by e-mail to [webmaster@sirs.com](mailto:webmaster@sirs.com) or by phone at (800) 232-7477. 

In SKS and Discoverer, Institution Contacts may request to receive e-mail notification of recent news and updates concerning SIRS products, request previews of newly released products, and change the Administration options for their current accounts. For the purpose of verifying that these requests are from Institutions, SIRS collects the following information: institution name, contact first and last name, contact title, e-mail address, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, fax number. 

## Use of Information

SIRS may use the Institutions information including e-mail for marketing and promotional purposes such as informing customers of product upgrades, special offers, updated information, and/or new services. SIRS may share Institution information with our agents. In addition, SIRS reserves the right to supply this information to an Institution's identified Internet Service Provider concerning blatant abuses or attempts to interfere with the functioning of our site. 

SIRS offers Institutions the option to request the following: (1) no longer receive marketing material by mail and (2) no longer receive marketing information by e-mail. If you would like to request removal from these lists, please e-mail [custserve@sirs.com](mailto:custserve@sirs.com) and include your name, institution, state, zip code and customer number. 

## Security

SIRS uses advanced security measures in connection with the collection and the transmission of Institution information. However, SIRS is not responsible for any breach of its security or for the actions of any third parties that may obtain any Institution information. SIRS will promptly evaluate and address all breaches in security. 

## External Linking

SIRS provides links to sites that we do not maintain. SIRS is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these sites. Institutions are responsible for the monitoring of minors after leaving the boundaries of our site. If any user should come across a link that may be considered objectionable, please contact [webmaster@sirs.com](mailto:webmaster@sirs.com). 

## Contacting SIRS

Thank you for reviewing SIRS Privacy Statement. If you have any questions or comments concerning this Privacy Statement please contact the Web Development Department of SIRS. 

**SIRS Publishing, Inc.**  
PO Box 272348  
Boca Raton, FL 33427-2348  
E-mail: [webmaster@sirs.com](mailto:webmaster@sirs.com)  
(800) 232-7477 (561) 994-0079 

SIRS reserves the right to change the information, policies, disclosures and disclaimers in this statement at any time. SIRS will post changes to the Privacy Policy on this Privacy Statement page ensuring that you always have access to what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. The continued use of SIRS Knowledge Source and SIRS Discoverer following the posting of changes to these terms will be considered an acceptance of any changes.
